JENNIFER ALEXANDER-HILL

3606 36th Ave W, Seattle, WA 98199 609-240-3935 jsa.wa.us@gmail.com

Profile

Highly creative and meticulously organized Development and Special Events professional. Motivated, personable, and diplomatic. Thrives in deadline-driven environments. Proven talent for quickly mastering new skills and scheduling tasks with an emphasis on efficiency. Extensive experience in Arts fundraising.

Skills Summary

• E +	പിപം	nina
Event	olan	1111115

Business/grant writing

Database management

Scheduling

Budgeting

Marketing/Web content

Computer savvy

Correspondence

VIP handling

Team player

Board management

•Excellent work ethic

Ticketing

Volunteer coordination

Social Media

Experience

ROCK BROOK SCHOOL

Marketing/Development Consultant – 2013-2014

- Developed full Marketing and Fundraising plans for the school.
- Developed Social Media plan and guidelines. Launched Facebook and Twitter accounts.
- Researched foundations for relevant grants.
- Planned and executed a large stewardship wine tasting event.
- Developed survey to assess effectiveness of current website and assisted with redesign.
- Wrote corporate sponsorship letters for wine tasting event.

PRINCETON UNIVERSITY ART MUSEUM

Manager of Corporate, Foundation, and Government Relations – 2010-2011 Development Specialist – 2012 (assisted with transition to replacement)

- Coordinated the Museum's fundraising efforts with corporations, foundations, and government supporters. Responsibilities included prospect research, cultivation, grant writing, reporting, and follow up.
 - Researched and wrote more than 40 Corporate, Foundation, and Government grant proposals, resulting in over one million dollars of support.
- Member of the Museum's Events Planning Team. Responsible for the overall
 coordination of a portion of the Museum's special events, e.g. opening receptions for
 exhibitions, cultivation dinners, and other events as assigned. Related tasks included
 budgeting, organization of invitation lists, development of invitation content,
 coordination of caterers and vendors, developing seating charts, preparing remarks, and
 overseeing events in progress.
- Additional projects.

- Member of Museum's Social Media Committee. Tweets and posts to Facebook on a weekly basis. Also provided creative content for the bi-weekly newsletter.
- Member of the Museum's Raiser's Edge Task Force. Assisted in the creation and implementation of a Best Practices program for the Museum's database users.
- Search Committee. Active member of search/hiring committees for two vital Museum positions.

PRINCETON UNIVERSITY ART MUSEUM

Museum Assistant – 2009-2010 (eight month temporary position)

- Writing correspondence for the Director.
- Scheduling meetings, including management of the Associate Director's calendar.
- Processing and tracking traveling exhibition proposals.
- Data entry and list management in Raiser's Edge.
- Special projects: grant writing, designed PARTNERS brochure, updating online calendars with Museum events, and assisting with interviews.

MCCARTER THEATRE CENTER, PRINCETON, NJ Stewardship and Events Director – 2006-2009

- Responsible for planning and implementation of all fundraising events, including cultivation dinners, Trustee events, donor events, and the annual Gala.
 - Surpassed the Gala income goal by \$40,000 in the first year netting \$210,000.
- Composed original material for proposals, press releases, ads, letters to the editor, reports, blog posts, RFPs, events trailers, donor letters, and web copy.
- Designed and crafted original and creative event materials including invitations, savethe-date cards, menus, place cards, brochures, fliers, and centerpieces.
 - Creator and manager of the Guitar Project and the Raindrops Project which brought celebrities, professional artists, and local artists together to create centerpieces and auction items for the annual Gala. These projects netted the theatre thousands of dollars in additional revenue and brought much needed publicity to the events.
- In charge of all Tessitura Software (database) projects for the Development department, including training, supervision of data entry, and enhancement projects.
- Designed a quarterly e-newsletter for donors.
- In charge of Opening Night VIP and Donor invitation lists, mailings, RSVPs, seating and ticketing.

Manager of Special Projects - 2005-2006

Maintained the responsibilities of my previous positions, with the addition of the following projects:

- Creator and manager of ACT II, a social group for donors between the ages of 25 and 45.
- Coordinated staffing and volunteer logistics for Annual Gala.
- Coordinated staff events, donor events and cultivation dinners.
- Launched and managed a Development research project using Larkspur Data's *Prospects of Wealth* to collect information on prospective donors. Worked with IT to develop new ways to track this information in Tessitura.
- Responsible for VIP ticketing for Major Donors and Trustees.

Acting Annual Fund Manager/Telefundraising Manager – 2005

While maintaining all the responsibilities of my full time position, took over for our Annual Fund manager during her eight month maternity leave.

Responsibilities and successes:

- Surpassed Annual Fund campaign goal of \$350,000.
- Managed and worked in-house telefundraising campaign which raised \$135,000.
- Compiled lists of donors to be solicited and composed campaign letters.
- Created several successful marketing promotions sent to subscribers and donors.
- Developed and implemented new system for tracking grant schedules and corporate solicitations in the Tessitura database.

Development Coordinator – 2003-2005

- Charged and batched all donations into database.
- Processed all acknowledgment letters and tax letters.
- Tracked all telefundraising solicitations.
- Prospect research on corporations and foundations.
- Served as McCarter's Volunteer Coordinator: responsible for recruiting volunteers and acted as staff liaison for the Associate Board, McCarter's volunteer board.
- Compiled and edited all donor listings for programs and donor boards.
- Managed budget for the Development department. In charge of coordinating quarterly forecast meetings and tracking all departmental expenses.
- Assisted with annual Gala, mini-benefit, opening nights, and donor events.

Conferences

2006 Tessitura Database Software Conference in Toronto

Presented on tracking donor research and moderated a Development forum.

2005 Tessitura Database Software conference in Boston

Presented on managing campaigns using solicitation tracking programs.

Education

Catholic University of America, Benjamin T. Rome School of Music

Washington, D.C., Bachelor of Music, Voice, equivalency minor in Theatre Arts Graduated with Honors

Princeton University, Manager Development Certificate program

Completed the following course work:

Managing Effective Interactions (Essentials of Leadership), Legal Aspects of Supervision, and Developing and Delivering Successful Presentations.

Natural Gourmet Institute

New York, NY, Profession Chef Training Program graduate